Guide to the Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies records, 1974-1986.
Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies records,1974-1986.
6756
Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies (U. S.).
4 cubic ft.
Printed Materials, Publications, Reports, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reports and legislation briefs, policy agendas, reports, and briefs. Subjects include women's issues, family farms, tax reform, community energy planning, local food, plant closings, cooperatives, South African divestment, toxic chemicals, and health care.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reports and legislation briefs, policy agendas, reports, and briefs. Subjects include women's issues, family farms, tax reform, community energy planning, local food, plant closings, cooperatives, South African divestment, toxic chemicals, and health care.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies (U. S.).
Subjects:
City planning--United States.; Family farms.; Tax reform.; Energy policy.; Energy conservation.; Plant shutdowns.; Cooperative societies.; Investments, American--South Africa.; Poisons.; Health planning.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
See also: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies digital collection, which consists of digitized readers from the physical collection, as well as additional material.
See also: Progressive Cities and Neighborhood Planning Collection, #15-2-3414
NOTES
Forms part of the Progressive Cities and Neighborhood Planning Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- Bernard, Sherman. The Manitoba Auto Insurance Plan. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Public Policies, 1971., 1971; 1; Report (Box 1)
  Descriptions of economic and social effects of the Manitoba Auto Insurance Plan.
- Webb, Lee (Ed.). Protecting the Family Farm/Preserving Farm Land. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, ca. 1975., ca. 1975; 2; Report (Box 1)
  Report on detrimental policies toward farms - policy descriptions, articles, and analysis.
- Simison, Robert. The Activist. Cleveland: Committee for New Political Initiatives, 1975., Ocober 1975; 3; Newsletter (Box 1)
  Newsletter: How to Rip-off the Federal Government Legally, briefs of actions in various states.
- Rhodes, Kathy. Legislative Handbook on Women's Issues. Washington D.C.: Institute for Policy Studies - Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1976., 1976; 4; Policy Report (Box 1)
  A Collection of Legislation on Economic Issues Affecting Women. Scenarios, legislation, and implementation steps in specific cities.
- Rowe, Jonathan;Beaudry, Ann (Ed.). New Directions in State & Local Tax Reform. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Public Policies, 1977., 1977; 5; Policy Agenda/Outline/Ideas (Box 1)
  Articles and arguments for tax reform.
- [no author provided] [various titles]. Washington D.C.: Women Today, 1977., May 16, 1977; 6; Magazine article (Box 1)
  Many summaries of recent actions concerning social equality.
- Kelly, Edward. Industrial Exodus: Public Strategies for Control of Corporate Relocation. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1977., October 1977; 7; Report (Box 1)
  Study of the transfer of business overseas; suggestions for maintaining economic strength in the states.
- Grune, Joy Ann (Ed.). Manual on Pay Equity: Raising Wages for Women's Work. Washington D.C.: Conference on State and Local Policies, 1981., November 1980; 8; Report (Box 1)
  Report on women's work experience in several different categories of the economy. Ideas for changes.
- Leibig, Michael. Social Investments and the Law - The Case for Alternative Investments. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1980., August 1980; 9; Report (Box 1)
  Studies in Pension Fund Investments 3 - Explorations of "The Law of Social Prudence" and investment strategies.
- Freedburg, Michael; Hughes,Ken. Meeting Local Needs: Resources for Self-Sufficiency. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., August 1981; 10; Report (Box 1)
  Community Skills and Resources - The Energy Project Report 3. Agencies and organizations that would contribute to sustaining CBOs.
- Brasuk, Danny; Glass, Becky; Mode, Suzanne. Local Alternative Energy Futures - Perspectives and Resources. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., June 1981; 11; Report (Box 1)
  Conference Proceedings December 11-13, 1980, Austin Texas.
- Dawson, Steve. Worker Cooperatives and the National Consumer Cooperative Bank Act. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies - Industrial Cooperative Association, 1979., 1979; 12; Document (Box 1)
  Outlines and summaries of worker cooperative organization and association with the NCCB.
- [no author provided] Innovative Energy Projects: A Briefing Book. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., August 1981; 13; Report (Box 1)
  Community Skills and Resources - The Energy Project Report 4. Agencies and organizations that would contribute to sustaining CBOs.
- Hyde, Henry; Kennedy, Maggie. New Initiatives in Farm, Land and Food Legislation - A State-by-State Guide: 1979-1980. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1979 - 80., 1979-1980; 14; Report (Box 1)
  Descriptions of new legislation for each state.
- Slavet, Julie. Energy Conservation - Resources. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1980., October 1980; 15; Report (Box 1)
  Lists of resources used for the Energy Project.
- Gordon, Erika; Logan, Patricia. The National Consumer Cooperative Bank: The First Year. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1981., July 1981; 16; Policy Analysis (Box 1)
  Analysis of Policies and Recommended Changes for the Cooperative Bank. NCCB Monitoring Report 1.
- Gordon, Erika; Logan, Patricia. The National Consumer Cooperative Bank: The First Year - Portfolio Analysis and Loan Recipient Survey. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1981., July 1981; 17; Report (Box 1)
  NCCB Monitoring Report 2
- Triplett, Thomas J.. Investing in Minnesota: A Proposal to Use State Moneys for Maximum Benefit. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1980., February 1980; 18 (Box 1)
  Studies in Pension Fund Investments 4.
- Smith, David. The Public Balance Sheet: A New Tool for Evaluating Economic Choices. Washington D.C. Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1979., July 1979; 19; Policy Report (Box 1)
  Public Policy report on economic development.
- Hughes, Ken; Pape, Barbara. Citizen Involvement in Community Energy Planning. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., August 1981; 20; Report (Box 1)
  Community Skills and Resources, Report 5. The Energy Project.
- Okagaki, Alan. State and Local Solar Energy Policy: Meeting Low-Income Needs. Washington D.C.: The Energy Project, Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., March 1981; 21; Report (Box 1)
  Public Policy Report- Descriptions of the effects of energy policy on low-income residents; some alternative state policy descriptions.
- Spielberg, Fred; Zinner, David. Portfolio Analysis and Loan Recipient Survey. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., March 1981; 22; Bank Report (Box 1)
  The National Consumer Cooperative Bank: The First Year. Co-op Develoment and Assistance Project.
- Scully, Michael. Massachusetts Public Land for Farms and Gardens - Innovative Legislation Series. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1979., 1979; 23; Legislation Brief (Box 1)
  Legislation brief from the Agriculture Project.
- Scully, Michael. Massachusetts Institutional Purchase of Local Food - Innovative Legislation Series. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., 1981; 24; Legislation Brief (Box 1)
- Scully, Michael. Interstate Grain Marketing Compact - Innovative Legislation Series. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1979., 1980-1981; 25; Legislation Brief (Box 1)
- Kelly, Edward. Plant Closings - Resources for Public Officials, Trade Unionists & Community Leaders. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., July 1981; 26; Report (Box 1)
  State-specific reports on reactions to major plant closings. A call for plant closing legislation.
- Schweke, William (Ed.). Plant Closings - Issues, Politics, and Legislation. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1980., January 1980; 27; Report (Box 1)
  Briefing Book, Economic Development Project. Tables, legislation descriptions, and analyses of the effects of plant closings.
- Webb, Lee (Ed.). Economic Development: New Ideas for the Midwest - Agenda '85. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1985., December 7, 1984; 28; Report (Box 1)
  Articles, summaries, analyses of policy ideas.
- [no author provided] Economic Development: New Ideas for the Missouri. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1985., February 14, 1985; 29; Report (Box 1)
- Kennedy, Maggie; Sherman, Jay. New Directions in Farm, Land and Food Policies: Legislative Update 1979. The Agriculture Project. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1979., 1979; 30; Report (Box 1)
  Lists of legislation pieces in different states.
- Schweke, William. Natural Resource Taxation - Perspectives, Resources & Issues. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1980., February 1980; 31; Report (Box 1)
  Briefing Book, Economic Development Project. Collection of articles.
- Various authors. California Farmworker Displacement Bill - Innovative Legislation Series. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1979., 1979; 32; Legislation Brief (Box 1)
- Various authors. Beginning Farmer Assitance Acts - Innovative Legislation Series. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1979., 1979; 33; Legislation Brief (Box 1)
- Freedburg, Michael; Slavet, Julie. New Initiatives in Energy Legislation - A State-by-State Guide: 1979-1980. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981 - 82., 1979-1980; 34; Report (Box 1)
- Sherman, Jay; Webb, Lee. Assisting Beginning Farmers: New Programs and Responses. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1980,81., 1980-81; 35; Briefing Book (Box 1)
  Briefing Book from the Agriculture Project.
- Marschall, Dan. The Battle of Cleveland: Public Interest Challenges Corporate Power. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1979., 1979; 36; Report (Box 1)
  Collection of articles during the Kucinich years.
- Estrella, Julia; Litwak, Lawrence; McTique, Kathleen. Divesting From South Africa: A Prudent Approach for Pension Funds. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., September 1981; 37; Policy Proposal (Box 1)
  Studies in Pension Fund Investments 10. Community Economics, Inc. Proposals.
- Pape, Barbara. New Initiatives in Energy Legislation - A State-by-State Guide: 1981-1982. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981 - 82., 1981-1982; 38; Report (Box 1)
- Weiss, Marc. Pension Fund Investments: The Issue of Control. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., January 1981; 39; Policy Study/Report (Box 1)
  Studies in Pension Fund Investments 5, Center for Economic Studies.
- [no author provided] Energy Planning and Education - A Handbook for Community Leaders and Organizations. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., 1981; 40; Handbook (Box 1)
  Descriptions of programs and ideas for energy initiatives.
- Bohannon, Mark; Webb, Lee. Model Legislation for the States: 1984-1985. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1984., 1984; 41; Report (Box 1)
  Summaries of proposed and written legislation for changed economic opportunity.
- Chess, Caron. Winning the Right to Know: A Handbook for Tovics Activists. Philadelphia: Deleware Valley Tocixs Coalition; Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1984., 1984; 42; Policy Agenda (Box 1)
  Informative booklet describing the toxic problems in an area of Philadelphia, ideas for regulation, and proposals for legislation.
- Freedburg, Michael. Cooperatives & Energy: New Co-ops and the National Consumer Co-op Bank. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1980., September 1980; 43; Pamphlet (Box 1)
  Pamphlet on cooperatives' role in saving energy.
- Various authors. Cooperatives and Energy - Annotated Bibliography and Resource Directory. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1980., 1980; 44; Directory/Bibliography (Box 1)
  The Energy Project and The Coop Bank Project
- Oberg, Keith (Ed.). Community Energy Cooperatives: How to Organize, Manage and Finance Them- An Organizer's Handbook. Washington D.C.: Co-op Development & Assistance Project Energy Project. Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1981., May 1981; 45; Handbook (Box 1)
  Handbook
- Vine, Edward. Solarizing America: The Davis Experience. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., August 1981; 46; Policy Report (Box 1)
  Public Policy Report 5, The Energy Project.
- Weiss, Marc. Pension Fund Investments: The Issue of Control. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1978., 1978; 47; Policy Study/Report (Box 1)
- Newman, Sandy. Ensuring Access to the Ballot: A Program for the States. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1983., December 1983; 48; Policy memo (Box 1)
  Policy memo
- Messinger, Ruth. Economic Development: An Agenda for the Cities. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1983., September 1983; 49; Policy memo (Box 1)
  Model Agenda: memo suggesting a new public policy initiative prepared for public officials, policy analysts, and civic leaders
- Webb, Lee. State and Local Tax Reform: An Agenda for States and Cities. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1982., June 1982; 50; Policy memo (Box 1)
  Model Agenda on a critical public policy issue prepared for public officias, civic leaders and activists
- Rosen, Corey. Employee Ownership: Issues, Resources and Legislation - A Handbook for Employees 7 Public Officials. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., August 1981; 51; Handbook (Box 1)
- Friedman, Bob. Small Business Development: An Agenda for States and Cities. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1983., January 1983; 52; Policy memo (Box 1)
- Newman, Sandy; Jones, David; Lizzaralde, Carlos. Voter Registration: An Agenda for the States. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1983., October 1983; 53; Policy memo (Box 1)
- Jones, David. Families: An Agenda for Cities and States. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1983., May 1984; 54; Policy memo (Box 1)
  Model Agenda on a critical public policy issue prepared for public officials, civic leaders and activists
- Del Giudice, Marguerite. Anniversary of the fight for 9 to 5 women. Boston: Boston Sunday Globe, Organization for Women Office Workers, 1978., November 5, 1978; 55; Newspaper article (Box 1)
  Photocopied newspaper article on a convention for working women.
- Timchick, Mary. Women stress organizing as economic key. Cleveland: Cleveland Press, 1978., May 18, 1978; 56; Newspaper article (Box 1)
  Photocopied newspaper article on women's organizations.
- [no author provided] Farm, Food, Land. Nashville, TN: Agricultural Marketing Project, 1979., January 1979; 57; Newspaper (Box 1)
  Excerpt from newspaper with various agriculture-related articles.
- [no author provided] Fair and Conference on the Mall, Washington D.C. Washington D.C.: Act 79, 1979., April 1979; 58; Program guide (Box 1)
  Program guide to a conference on renewing resources, sustainability, and best-practice methods.
- Various authors. Coop Bank Conferences. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1978., June 1978; 59; Conference materials (Box 1)
  Folder of conference materials.
- Various authors. Cooperatives and Energy - New Coops and The National Consumer Coop Bank. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1980., 1980; 60; Report (Box 1)
- Cooperatives & Energy: Annotated Bibliography and Resource Directory. Washington, D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., April 1981; 61; Directory/Bibliography (Box 1)
  The Co-op Development and Assistance Project, The Energy Project - bibliography and contact info.
- Various authors. Various Working Papers and Publications, Annotated Bibliographies. Wellesley: Center for Research on Women, 1979., July 1979; 62; Bibliography (Box 1)
  Collection of bibliographies
- Various authors. Various Conference Materials and Publications by the National Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, ca. 1979; 63; Collection of documents (Box 1)
  Collection of documents
- Beaudry, Ann. Letter to Doyle Niemann, April 18, 1978; 64; Letter (Box 1)
  Letter about a "Women in the Economy" Conference in Cleveland.
- [no author provided] City accused on longtime job bias. Cleveland: Sunday Plain Dealer, 1978., May 14, 1978; 65; Newspaper article (Box 1)
  Newspaper article describing the racial and sexual discrimination against a woman in Cleveland.
- Various authors. [various titles]. New York: Newlestter of The Democratic Left, 1978., April 1978; 66; Newsletter (Box 1)
  Newsletter
- Various authors. Chicana Women Organize; Violence Against Abortion Rights; The Baby Formula Scandal. Washington D.C.: Women's Agenda, 1978., April 1978; 67; Publication (Box 1)
  Publication focusing on women's issues and movements.
- Beaudry, Ann. Women in the Economy: Policies and Strategies for Change. Washington D.C.: The Executive Female Digest, 1978., May 1978; 68; excerpt from Magazine (Box 1)
  Brief description of a meeting on women's economic experiences sponsored by the Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies.
- Various Authors. Updates on State Initiatives, ca.1986; 69; Research materials (Box 1)
  Collection of handwritten notes attached to articles, memos, and reports: Tax Reform in Ohio, Family Planning in Maryland, Environmental Initiatives in California, Weapons and War in Minnesota, Taxes and Revenue in Washington D.C., Lifeline Services In Washington D.C., Housing in New York, Economic Conversion in Minnesota, Environment in New York, Recycling in Illinois. Contact Information provided
- Baker, Lawrence; Bluestone, Barry; Harrison, Bennett. Corporate Flight - The Causes and Consequences of Economic Dislocation. Washington D.C.: Progressive Alliance, National Center for Policy Alternatives, Working Papers for a New Society, 1981., March 1, 1981; 70; Book (Box 1)
  Analytical book
- Hartman, Chester. Letter to Lee Webb, April 1978; 71; Letter (Box 1)
  Letter about the Planner's Netwokr; update on projects and people.
- Gautier, Duane. Meeting Local Needs: Technical Resources for Self-Sufficiency. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., October 1981; 72; Report (Box 1)
  Community Skills and Resources - The Energy Project. Agencies and organizations that would contribute to sustaining CBOs.
- Hughes, Ken; Pape, Barbara. Innovative Energy Projects: Models for Self-Sufficiency. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., October 1981; 73; Policy Proposal (Box 1)
  Community Skills and Resources, The Energy Project. Assessments and Plans for Community Participation in saving energy.
- The Coop Bank: New Funds for Community Development: Washington D.C.: Conference/Alternative State & Local Policies, 1978., April 1, 1978; 74; Legislation Brief (Box 1)
  Section-by-section summary of the Coop Bank Act
- Peirce, Neal R. & Hagstrom, Jerry. Watch Out, New Right, Here Come the 'Young Progressives'- National Journal Political Report. Washington D.C.: Conference/Alternative State & Local Policies, 1978., December 30, 1978; 75; Journal Political Report (Box 1)
  Article w/ description of the ideals of the upcoming social activists such as philosophy, conference activities, initiatives & groups
- Kieschnick, Michael & Katzmann, Lynne S.. Policy Memo- 1981 & 1983 Memorandums. Washington D.C: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1981., May 10, 1981, January 1983; 76; Policy Memorandum (Box 1)
  2 legislation memorandums- #1: Developing A State Venture Capital Strategy (Kieschnick, May10, 1981). #2: A Pro-Competitive Model for a Statewide Health Insurance Program: The Oregon Proposal (Katzmann, January, 1983)
- Schweke, William & Webb, Lee. Putting America Back To Work: What States & Cities Can Do: Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1982., 1982; 77; Policy Handbook (Box 1)
  Documented summary of employment issues in the U.S.- 4 sections including new work strategies, access to employment for the disadvantaged, assisting the unemployed, worker rights; organizational resources: 74 pages
- Logan, Patricia (Ed.). Community Energy Cooperatives: How to Organize, Manage and Finance Them- An Organizer's Handbook. Washington D.C.: Co-op Development & Assistance Project Energy Project. Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies. Revised Edition, 1982., 1982; 78; Policy Handbook (Box 1)
  Revised edition from 1980 Original print. Documented summary for alternatives to the energy crisis- 8 sections including problems, cooperatives, case studies, organizing, finance, business planning, plus Appendix A-E & glossary: 229 pages
- Leibig, Michael. Mandating Social Prudence: A Handbook for Pension Investment- Studies in Pension Fund Investment 12. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1982., February 1, 1982; 79; Policy Handbook (Box 1)
  Documented summary of Pension Investment issues- 4 sections including pension plan creation, regulation, implementation, & administration, plus intro & conclusion, and Appendix A-B: 99 pages
- Moore, Nancy. The National Consumer Cooperative Bank: Eligibility: How Co-ops and Community Organizations Can Use The Co-op Bank- NCCB Monitoring Report 4: Co-op Development And Assistance Project. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternatives State & Local Policies, 1982., September 1982; 80; Policy Handbook (Box 1)
  Manual providing step-by-step info regarding eligibility for fund from the NCCB- 5 sections plus Appendix and 6 Exhibits: 56 pages
- Conference Reports. Wisconsin: Alternative State & Local Policies, 1975., June 13-15, December 5-7, 1975; 81; Conference Report (Box 1)
  2 conference reports- #1: Where Do We Go From Here?...Conference Report. 13/14/15 June 1975. Madison, Wisconsin (Report prepared by Barbara Bick). #2: Southwest Regional Conference. Dec.5-7, 1975.
- Webb, Lee. State Bank for Coops: A Proposal to Establish a State Bank for Cooperatives and a State Cooperative Development Agency. Washington D.C.: Institute for Policy Studies, 1975., October 1975; 82; Policy Proposal (Box 1)